<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-31T22:09:11-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Marvin Lin</title><subtitle>Hello friends! Welcome to my digital home. This is where you can find a bit more about what I do, some of my ongoing projects, and also read my essays.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Restart</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/essays/restart" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Restart" /><published>2021-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/essays/restart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/essays/restart">&lt;p&gt;This is my promise to myself. I’ve let the fear of an unasthetic website for my writings taunt me for too long – today marks the day I begin writing regularly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="other" /><summary type="html">This is my promise to myself. I’ve let the fear of an unasthetic website for my writings taunt me for too long – today marks the day I begin writing regularly.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bias and Power</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/essays/bias-and-power" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bias and Power" /><published>2021-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/essays/bias-and-power</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/essays/bias-and-power">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note that these are my opinions, thoughts, and perspectives at one point of time. These thoughts may be wrong or change over time. The intent of these thoughts is to drive discussion, not hate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everyone-is-capable-of-holding-and-acting-on-racial-bias-what-happens-when-people-in-positions-of-power-with-the-ability-to-harm-decide-to-act-on-their-racial-bias&quot;&gt;Everyone is capable of holding and acting on racial bias. What happens when people in positions of power with the ability to harm decide to act on their racial bias?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bias, racial or non racial, will always exist in us. Often times, we will act on them because it’s the path of least resistance. However, this doesn’t mean you cannot a) acknowledge your bias and b) separate yourself from bias through education to the best of your ability. This is true regardless of who you are and what power you have. In the case of those with high power by any means (a CEO, police officer, etc.), there lies a greater responsibility to actively acknowledge bias and seek to remove oneself from this bias. By acting on ones bias, it can and will violate the trust given to them by those (often times the general public) who bestow the power upon them. Consequences, as we’ve seen, often times is the removal of this power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-justice-look-like&quot;&gt;What does justice look like?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-it-mean-to-be-held-accountable&quot;&gt;What does it mean to be held accountable?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-we-extend-care-to-each-other-in-times-of-trauma-and-crisis&quot;&gt;How do we extend care to each other in times of trauma and crisis?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In regards to both questions, I want to emphasize the importance of genuine care in the actions that are taken to hold people accountable and extending care to others. Sadly, more often than not, organizations and people will appear to hold those accountable and/or appear to extend care, for the sake of PR, for the sake of making themselves “look good” in these times of trauma and crisis. I don’t want to assume and say who and/or what actions others have taken and label them as “PR” or purely for their own public image, but the reality is when many of these events pass over, nothing is beyond, constant support – “fake friends” and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;perspective-and-media&quot;&gt;Perspective and Media&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;removing-bias&quot;&gt;Removing Bias&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educate and have conversations, acknowledging is not surrendering or admitting weakness, but is rather strength in the ability to improve oneself
Ask what their needs are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Narrative about talk with Delplance removal from self&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-importance-of-discussions&quot;&gt;The Importance of Discussions&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="race" /><category term="injustice" /><summary type="html">Please note that these are my opinions, thoughts, and perspectives at one point of time. These thoughts may be wrong or change over time. The intent of these thoughts is to drive discussion, not hate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflecting on My Skin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/essays/my-skin" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflecting on My Skin" /><published>2020-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/essays/my-skin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/essays/my-skin">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A reflection of race, the impact on my daily life, and the world we live in. Inspired by Neil deGrasse Tyson’s article “Reflections on the Color of My Skin”, Marques Brownlee, or MKBHD’s video “Reflecting on the Color of My Skin”, and Hasan Minhaj’s video, “We cannot stay silent about George Floyd”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;460&quot; src=&quot;/my-skin.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;max-width: 460px; margin: auto; font-size: 12px;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Minneapolis officers Thomas Lane, Alexander Kueng and Tou Thao. Photo from Hennepin County Sheriff's Office&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often classify the protests, anger, and violence around social injustice, particularly surrounding Black Rights, or better known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/blacklivesmater?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Ehashtag&quot;&gt;#BlackLivesMatter&lt;/a&gt;, to be a black on white issue. More often than not, the Asian American community sits on the sidelines, watching the action unfold. On occasion, some step onto the field, provide their support, and step out. We don’t play the game, but rather only intervene when the scoreboard tells us to. Only in times where such heartbreaking and grotesque news becomes of a national presence, do we step in. We feel that there is an external pressure of friends on Instagram or Twitter posting about the issues on racial injustice, then step in. Do we not have enough of a role in this problem to reflect on how we, as Asian Americans, play a role in extending the issue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reading the sickening story of George Floyd, the media tends to focus on the black on white racism, the actions done by the singular police officer who had pinned his knee into the neck of Geroge Floyd for over eight minutes. What is often missed, is the Asian American officer who stood at the scene, keeping other civilians at bay. This is not a black on white problem. This is a national issue. Just like COVID-19, racism has no boundaries and can exist everywhere: Friends, coworkers, and even family. The specific instance of now-former Minneapolis police officer Tou Thao is a glaring example of how interwoven we, Asian Americans, are part of this problem. Maybe Asian Americans involved in racists acts are not the headlines of racial injustice, but the media does not dictate the impact of our actions. Understand that we, just like any other race, are factors in racism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether this consists of perpetuating generalizations made about Black, White, Asian, or any other American, or achieves a severity of violence, all of these actions contribute to the parasite of racism in our nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the primary focus of many of these protests in on changing the law enforcement systems, I urge all of you to look beyond these surface symptoms of a greater problem in our nation. Yes, the issue of brutality is critical at this point in time—especially towards blacks. There is no denying that we need to see a change in policy at a national and local level. However, why do these issues continue to rise? The training of officers is a significant factor in progress, but the great majority of issues come from the underlying racism in society. Coming from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racism_in_the_United_States&quot;&gt;a background of racial conflict&lt;/a&gt;, we must consider the residual effects of our past. Even the seemingly small acts of racial injustice are hints at the roots of racism deep in our nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting from a young age, I consistently interacted with a diverse group of people. My first year of traditional schooling at Springville K-8 began my journey through life, with all of these people. White, Asian, Black—the diversity in students throughout my educational journey is one I often take for granted, yet is the primary reason I have often have little consideration of race in my judgment, rather value them as people, brothers, and sisters. As a result of this consistent interaction, you realize that each and every person, no matter the color of their skin, is just like you. They play the same games on the playground, they eat lunch at the same table, they sit at the same desks at you. Although each individual is unique in their culture and heritage, they are all human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At five years old, there was no analysis. It was instinctive to consider any fellow student as a friend. The color of their skin made no difference to me. We could all learn a thing or two from our younger selves: real experiences tell the truth that words might not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It concerns me that many find the solution to be attacking the people who were and are involved in these problems. Although it is absolutely true that people perpetuate the conflict, the inherent issue is often confused with the people who have been affected by such evil. Martin Luther King states in his article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://kinginstitute.stanford.edu/king-papers/documents/nonviolence-and-racial-justice&quot;&gt;Nonviolence and Racial Justice&lt;/a&gt;, “It is evil we are seeking to defeat, not the persons victimized by evil”. Attacking the people who have been infected by racism does not address the issue but is rather counterproductive. Before we make accusations, attack others, or fight, we must identify the true enemy: the parasite of racism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask all of you to consider the following: What drives the core of this injustice? What can be done?  In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/ex-minneapolis-cop-told-other-officers-you-shouldn-t-do-n1225136&quot;&gt;NBC News article&lt;/a&gt;, Officer Lane’s lawyer Earl Gray asks, “What is my client supposed to do other than follow what the training officer said?” What would happen if law enforcement training was more robust, especially in regards to racial profiling? Would George Floyd, Ahmaud Arbery, and countless others, have been killed?  Most importantly, how can we enact this change?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that the publicity and popularity of the death of George Floyd will die down in the coming weeks. The social media hype will diminish like it always does. The fight for justice and the parasite of racism in our nation should not end. I urge all of you to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call our governmental leaders to act—legislation is a driving force in change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vocalize. How have you faced injustice? How should this change?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read and listen. Become educated on the issues of injustice, as being knowledgeable can mean the world of a difference in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond calling our leaders in government to change our justice and law enforcement systems, I urge all of you to reflect upon yourself as I have today. In what ways have you been judged by the color of your skin? In what ways have you judged others? Think about your friends. Are they different in such a significant way that they should be treated differently? What privileges do you have over others? Regardless of your answers, simply remember: you only fail when you refuse to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A racist is one who refuses to acknowledge privilege and fight change, while an American is one who recognizes their privilege and supports change. &lt;strong&gt;Who do you choose to be?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="race" /><category term="injustice" /><summary type="html">A reflection of race, the impact on my daily life, and the world we live in. Inspired by Neil deGrasse Tyson’s article “Reflections on the Color of My Skin”, Marques Brownlee, or MKBHD’s video “Reflecting on the Color of My Skin”, and Hasan Minhaj’s video, “We cannot stay silent about George Floyd”.</summary></entry></feed>